片名：诸神之怒
远古时代 这个世界曾由神魔所统治
In ancient times, the world was ruled by gods and monsters.
但它却是我的儿子 - 半神珀尔修斯
But it was the half-god Perseus, my son...
打败了北海巨妖 拯救了人类
...who defeated the Kraken and saved humanity.
为了奖励他的勇敢 我在身边为他安排了一个神位
For his courage, I offered him a place to rule at my side.
但珀尔修斯…
But Perseus...
固执己见 做出了另外的选择
strong-willed and chose a different path
他发誓以人的身份生活
He vowed to live as a man.
即使命运夺去了他的妻子
Even when fate took his wife...
他仍不愿向我…
...he would not pray for help, from me...
或其他诸神祈求帮助
...or the other gods.
如今神的时代已近结束
And now the time of the gods is ending.
但宙斯之子却不能永远逃避自己的命运
But the son of Zeus cannot hide from his destiny forever.
现在拉它回来.再做一次
New pull it in. Dc it again.
快点把另一个也扔出去 继续 我把这个打个结
Throw in the other one real quick. Go on. I'll tie this off.
今天收获不错 爸爸
Goad catch today, Dad.
- 你从哪儿弄的那个东西？ - 我自己做的
- Where'd you get that? - I made it myself.
你自己做的？
You made it yourself? Heh.
我想做个好神 做些好事
I want to be a good god and do good things.
- 没有什么好神 - 有一些神是好的
- There's no such thing as good gods.- Some of them are good.
赫利俄斯 生活中不是只有神和泰坦
Ah. Helius, there's more to life than gods and Titans.
嘿 克莉亚 我要跟你认个错
Hey, Clea. I have a confession to make.
我刚才 嗯…需要他帮忙做事 所以他没来学习
I, uh, needed him for chores so he skipped studying.
现在 去好好学习 让我骄傲一下
Now, you do a good jab, make me proud.
我知道你在这儿
I know you're here.
我时常在他熟睡时来看他
I visit him sometimes in his dreams.
他就像他的父亲一样 一个意志坚强的孩子
He's like his father. A strong-willed bay.
你是顺路过来看看？
You just passing through?
不是
Na.
我需要你的帮助
I need your help...
珀尔修斯
...Perseus.
你是万物之神宙斯 你不需要我的帮助
You're the great god Zeus. You don't need my help.
大灾变即将降临
There is a calamity coming.
它会影响到我们所有人 无论是神还是人
It will affect us all. Gods and men.
- 人类将不再向我们祈祷 - 理由不错
- The humans may have stopped praying to us... - With good reason.
但是会有后果发生
...but there are consequences.
没有了祈祷者 我们众神将失去力量
Without prayer, we gods lose our power.
当我们失去力量时 所有的努力都将付之一炬 所有的一切…
When our power leaves us, all our work comes undone. All of it.
地狱深渊的壁垒将崩塌
The walls of Tartarus are falling.
所有地狱中的恶魔将倾巢涌入凡间 第一个恶魔已经出现了
It is emptying all its demons onto the earth. The first are already here.
如果我们的力量进一步减弱  我们众神将沦为凡人
If our power diminishes much further, we gods will became mortal.
我们将会死去 库洛纳斯将会逃脱
We will die and Kronos himself will escape.
到那时会秩序混乱 即是世界的末日
It will mean chaos. The end of the world.
我能做些什么？
What am I meant to do?
这是神的事
This is business for gods.
如今我们需要我们所有的孩子
We need all our children now.
或许 团结一致
Perhaps, together...
我们就能补救这一切
...we can remedy this.
但我们需要每一份绵薄之力 珀尔修斯
But we need every shred of power, Perseus.
我不会丢下我的孩子
I will never leave my sun.
我比你更加了解你自己
I know your heart better then you know it yourself.
你一直相信 你人性的一面告诉你加入我们是不值得的
You believe your human half makes you unworthy to join us.
终有一日你会了解
You will learn someday that...
作为一个半神
...being half-human...
你比真神更加强大 而不是嬴弱
...makes you stranger than a god, not weaker.
我觉得你该走了
I think you should go.
好梦 珀尔修斯
Sleep well, Perseus.
我不会丢下我的孩子
I will never leave my son.
宙斯
Zeus.
波塞冬
Poseidon.
兄弟
Brother.
好久不见
It has been an age.
确实 很久了
Indeed, it has.
阿瑞斯
Ares.
我的孩子
My sun.
我的兄弟珀尔修斯在哪儿？
Where's my brother Perseus?
去打鱼了？
Gone fishing?
是的
Yes.
多么勇敢而高尚的决定
What a brave and noble decision.
那么 我们走
Let us go, then.
地狱深渊 冥界最大的监狱
Tartarus. The great prison of the underworld.
哈迪斯兄弟
Brother Hades!
我们依照协定
We have came to your domain...
来到了你的管辖区
...as agreed!
现身吧
Show yourself to us!
这么多年来
After so many years...
库洛纳斯的孩子们 再一次重聚
the sons of Kronos, together once more.
手足兄弟
Brothers in arms.
哈迪斯
Hades...
你是冥界最高的统治者
you are the great ruler of the underworld.
请允许我们进入并帮助你重建
Allow us to enter and help you rebuild...
地狱深渊的壁垒
...the walls of Tartarus.
我亲爱的兄弟 是你将我永远驱逐到这里
My beloved brother, who banished me here for eternity...
照顾我们的父亲 而如今
...to lack after our father, new seeks...
却要寻求和解
...reconciliation.
兄弟 我们要忘记过去
We must forget the past, brother...
团结一致
...and unite.
没错
Yes.
但是我说了算
But an my terms.
波塞冬
Poseidon!
在你上面
Above you!
波塞冬
Poseidon.
已经开始了
It has begun.
赫利俄斯？
Helius?!
赫利俄斯
Helius!
离它远点 离它远点
Stay away, stay away!
赫利俄斯？
Helius?
赫利俄斯
Helius.
怪兽
Chimera!
赫利俄斯
Helius!
你有看到赫利俄斯么?!
Have you seen Helius?!
赫利俄斯
Helius!
回来
Get back!
不要接近它会喷火
Keep away! Its venom catches fire!
趴下
Stay dawn!
赫利俄斯 跟他们走
Helius, go with them!
带走他
Take him!
我会找到你的走啊
I'll find you! Go!
快走!
Go!
- 爸爸 - 快走
- Dad! Run!
快走
Go!
赫利俄斯
Helius!
- 爸爸 快 - 我来了 儿子
Dad, hurry! I'm coming, son!
赫利俄斯呆那儿别动
Helius! Stay there!
爸爸
HELIUS Dad!
赫利俄斯
Helius!
在这儿
Here!
来抓我啊
Came and get me!
你在等什么？烧死我啊
What are you waiting for?! Burn me!
坐下
Sit.
哦
Ohh.
在这个世界上
Things are happening...
已经有事开始发生了 珀尔修斯 你知道的 我能感受得到
...in the world, Perseus. You know that, you have instincts.
神之子
The sun of a god.
儿子需要父亲
A sun needs a father.
我曾对妻子发誓
I made a vow to la.
我懂 我懂 你孩子出生时候我在场
I know, I know, I was there delivering your sun.
你曾对你的妻子发誓 你永远不会让赫利俄斯使用武器
You vowed to your wife you'd never let Helius wield a sword.
你将与他一起作为打渔生活
That you'd live with him as a simple fisherman.
没错 和平时期这么做确实没错
Well, that's a fine game in normal times.
但是如果你有了力量 你也就有了责任
But if you have power, you also have a duty.
把我的身子治好
Just fix my body...
我的灵魂我自己做主
...and leave my soul to me.
你们要去哪儿？
Where are we going?
我要和我的父亲谈谈
I need to speak to my father.
没有什么好害怕的
There's nothing to be frightened cf.
这里就是万神殿
This is the Mount of Idols.
距离天堂最近的地方
The closest place to the heavens.
这儿就是人们来拜祭众神的地方
It's a place where people came to warship the gods.
至少他们曾经来过
Or at least they used to came.
宙斯？
Zeus?
父亲
Father.
波塞冬
Poseidon.
发生了什么？
What happened?
哈迪斯和阿瑞斯已经加入了库洛纳斯
Hades and Ares have joined Kronos...
共同对付人类
...against humanity.
所有的神都已经消失不见
All the gods have disappeared.
- 我最怕出现的情况 - 来 过来
- I fear the worst. - Here, here.
我扶着你
I got you, I got you.
我父亲在哪儿？
Where's my father?
被抓了
Captured.
你必须到冥界去解救他
You must journey to the underworld and free him.
他们抓走了我的父亲
They tank my father.
你是这个世界尚存的唯一希望
You're the only hope left in this world.
不然就全完了
Or there will be oblivion.
我该怎么做？
How do I do it?
我只是一个半神
I'm only half a god.
那你就要找到另一个半神
Then you must find another half-god.
阿格诺尔
Agenor.
他是我的儿子
He's my sun.
他和安德洛墨达公主在一起
He's with Queen Andromeda.
让他带你去找堕落者
Tell him to take you to the Fallen One.
波塞冬
Poseidon.
拿着这个 使用它
Take this. Use it.
如果我的儿子
If my sun...
能够活下来 就证明我把这个传给他
...survives and proves worthy...
是值得的
...give it to him.
我的亲儿子背叛了我
My awn sun betrays me.
只有你觉得情况合适时  你才会记得我就是你的儿子
Only when it suits you, you remember I am your son.
哈迪斯
Hades.
兄弟 你像个人类一样流汗 接下来 就会流泪
You're sweating like a human, brother. Next, it'll be tears.
别跟他废话
Don't waste wards an him.
库洛纳斯在等着
Kronos is waiting...
父亲
...Father.
怎么了？
What?
我们的父亲向我们提出一个交易
Our father has offered us a deal.
你个笨蛋
You foal!
如果我们能帮助他逃离地狱深渊
If we help him to escape Tartarus...
他答应允许我们少数几个神保持神性
...he will allow we few gods who remain to keep our immortality.
- 不! - 让他说话
- Na! - Let him speak.
让他说话
Let him speak.
你是不是变弱了？
Are you becoming weak?
你现在在冥界 阿瑞斯 我的地盘 你最好听我的
You're in the underworld, Ares, where it's wise to obey me.
我们的父亲曾想杀掉我们 你忘记了？
You forget our father once tried to kill us.
没有 我什么都记得
Na, I remember everything.
我们的父亲究竟想从我们这里得到什么？ 而回报是宝贵的神性
And what exactly does our father want from us in return for our precious immortality?
我们仅仅是把你仅存的圣神力量提供给他 这样他就能让自己自由
We simply offer him the last of your divine powers so that he may free himself.
哦 哈迪斯
Oh, Hades.
我都对你做了什么？
What have I done to you?
你笑得好像你还有选择
You laugh as if you had a choice.
没有选择了
There is no choice.
我希望你已经受够他们了
I hope you have enough of them.
拉他起来
Pull him.
你比我更需要它
You'll need it more than me.
天马
Pegasus.
去吧
Go on.
他喜欢你
He likes you.
而我 在另一方面
Me, on the other hand...
我爱你
I love you.
我知道
I know.
走吧
Came an.
嘿 哇 向前直飞 干得不错
Eh, whoa. Keep it straight. Have it lack good.
来吧 伙计
Came an, bay.
更多怪兽弓箭手
More Chimera! Archers!
快 快 快
Go, go, go!
准备发射
Ready! Fire!
怪兽 准备
Chimera! Ready!
保持队形 保持队形
Hold your lines. Hold your lines!
让开路
Out of the way!
停止攻击
Hold your fire!
我命令你们停止攻击
- I said hold your fire! Queen Andromeda.
啊 保持直线飞 就这样
Ah, keep it straight. Oy!
哇
Whoa!
你以前可比这厉害多了
You used to be a lot better at this.
全体向您致敬 珀尔修斯 北海巨妖杀手
All hail Perseus, killer of the Kraken.
向您致敬 珀尔修斯
Hail Perseus!
伟大的珀尔修斯
Great Perseus.
如果你追求的是战斗 你有点来晚了
If it is action you're after, you are a little late.
我只是来参见安德洛墨达公主的
I'm just here to see Queen Andromeda.
这里是战场
This is a battlefield.
这儿我是指挥官 嗯
- I am in command here. - Uh-huh.
好吧 我想和公主谈谈
Well, I wish to speak to the queen.
正好公主也有话要和你谈谈
And the queen wishes to speak to you.
女王殿下
Your Majesty.
来吧
Came an.
向您致敬 珀尔修斯
Hail Perseus.
很明显你身处自己的战争中 珀尔修斯
You've obviously been in your own battles, Perseus.
我也正忙着打我的战争
I've been busy with mine.
是的 没错
Yeah, you have.
我不会勉强你
I won't keep you.
都过去很久了
It's been tan lung.
- 我现在有一个儿子 - 我知道 我想见见他
- I have a sun now. - I know. I'd like to meet him.
- 我的妻子 她… - 我知道
And my wife, she... - I know.
很抱歉
I'm sorry.
女王殿下
Your Majesty.
为了人类 我们必须在日落前解决我们的分歧
For the sake of the men, we must resolve our differences before sunset.
我说的很清楚 我会继续战斗
I made it clear we continue to fight...
抵抗怪兽入侵
...the Chimera invaders.
今天在战场我们失去了300人
Today in the field we last 300 men...
而目前只杀掉了4头怪兽 我们
...for the death of four Chimera. We have...
触怒了众神.我们需要祈祷
offended the gods. We need to pray.
也许 你要向战神阿瑞斯祈祷？
You'd pray to Ares, perhaps?
战士们都会这么做
As soldiers always have.
如果我告诉你阿瑞斯现在是你们的敌人 你怎么想？
What if I was to tell you that Ares is your enemy now?
我会同他讲和
I would make peace with him.
你想同战神讲和？
You would make peace with the god of war?
珀尔修斯
Perseus.
你有什么战略？
What's your strategy?
有一种方法我们可以解决这一切 然后平安回家
There's a way we can end this, and then I can get home.
- 你这是要干什么？ - 我要为我的战船刻船舱
- What is this far? - It's to cut the cars for my trireme.
我需要110间船舱
I need 110 cars...
目前这三行
...for the three rows...
每行一个人
...one oar per man.
这个看起来像偷的
This lacks like a pick.
- 没错 但它是我船上的方向舵 - 安静
- It is, however, the rudder for my flagship.- Quiet!
早间审讯 女王殿下
Morning checks, Your Majesty.
总是充满变故
Always eventful.
哦 女王殿下 很高兴见到你
Oh, Your Majesty. Ah. Sc good to see you.
这就是阿格诺尔 他是个骗子 也是个贼 我知道我们之间不可能
- This is Agenor. He's a liar and a thief. I know it didn't work out between us...
但是 请 试着忘记它吧
...but, please, do try and get over it.
你有没有一个如此深爱你的女人
Have you ever had a woman love you so much...
她会像宠物兔子一样把你绑起来？
...she lacks you up like a pet rabbit?
他想通过婚姻关系寻求我的帮助
He wanted my hand in marriage.
当我拒绝时 他设法带着皇冠上的珠宝逃走
When I refused, he tried to run away with the crown jewels.
我想这就是因为我非凡的眼睛
I think it's my extraordinary eyes.
实际上 你有你父亲的眼睛
Actually, you gut the eyes of your father.
你认识他父亲？
Do you know his father?
是的 这个阿格诺尔
Yeah, Agenor here...
他是海神波塞冬的儿子
...he's the son of the great god Poseidon.
你的新男朋友很明显疯掉了
Your new boyfriend is clearly insane.
我是你的兄弟  阿格诺尔
I'm your cousin, Agenor.
我是宙斯的儿子
I'm the sun of Zeus.
我是半神 和你一样被遗弃了
Half-god and abandoned just like you.
如果是我的父亲派你来
If my father sent you...
我不想跟你有任何瓜葛
...I want nothing to do with you.
你的父亲已经死了
Your father is dead.
神是不会死的
Gods don't die.
如今他们确实会
They do now.
好啊 能帮我个忙么？
Goad. Could you do me a favor?
- 任何事 - 下地狱去吧
Anything. - Go to hell.
那正是我要做的事
That's exactly where I'm going.
我只是需要些信息
I just need information.
你的父亲告诉我说
Your father told me...
你能帮助我找到堕落者
...that you could help me get to the Fallen One.
你很向往大海 不是么？
You long for the ocean, don't you?
就像是永远无法解除的饥渴感
It's like a thirst you cannot quench.
在这儿对你来说就是地狱
It must be hell for you in here.
我要皇家赦免
I want a royal pardon.
同意
Granted.
我要和我体重一样重的金子
I want my body weight in gold.
同意
Granted.
Few gold coins, you're so scrawny. 几乎没有金币 你太瘦了
Few gold coins, you're so scrawny.
让我想想 当我在监狱里躺着的时候 还梦到了什么？
Let me see. What else have I dreamt of as I lay here in my cell?
别太过分了
Don't push it.
我需要一条船 你这儿最快的船
I'm gonna need a boat, your fastest boat.
堕落者住在海洋那边很远的地方
The Fallen One lives far across the ocean.
在哪儿？
Where?
当我双脚踏上船板的时候 我会告诉你
Well, put me on the deck of the boat and I'll show you.
你的船在等你
Your ship awaits.
把我的幸运斗篷拿来
Fetch my lucky cape.
老家伙 你知道为什么这个叫我的幸运斗篷么？
Do you know why this is my lucky cape, me old mate?
因为我第一次穿它的时候 我开始长胡子 密密麻麻的胡子
Because the first time I ware it, I sprouted a beard. A full-grown beard.
给每个军团的人发消息
Send ward to every regiment...
在帝龙关口集合的命令仍然不变
...that's still intact to gather here at the Tyrene pass.
如果两天后我不在这儿
If I'm not there in two days...
你就可以祈祷了
...then you can pray.
女王殿下
Your Majesty.
- 要塞重新编队 - 你不能
Regroup at the garrison! You can't leave...
让希腊没有公主
...Greece without a queen.
你是在对我下命令么？
Are you giving me orders now?
把他解开
Unchain him.
告诉我堕落者在哪儿
Show me where the Fallen One is.
谁是堕落者？
Who is the Fallen One?
哦 是火神赫淮斯托斯 哦 哦
Oh, the god Hephaestus. Heh, heh.
谁是赫淮斯托斯？
And who's Hephaestus?
赫淮斯托斯为海神波塞冬做了三叉戟
Hephaestus was the god that made Poseidon's trident...
为冥王哈迪斯做了草叉
Hades' pitchfork...
还为宙斯做了闪电剑
...and Zeus' thunderbolt.
所有这些放在一起
Put those together...
成为胜利之矛 众神用来击败库洛纳斯
...they farm the Spear of Trium, the weapon the gods used...
的武器
to defeat Kronos.
但是赫淮斯托斯住在凯尔之岛 哈哈
But Hephaestus lives on the island of Kail. Ha-ha-ha.
没有人知道岛在哪儿
Which no one has ever found.
凯尔岛不存在 是么？阿格诺尔
Kail doesn't exist, does it, Agenor'?
它确实
It dues...
存在 我能带你去那
...exist. I can take you.
帮我解开 把三叉戟给我
Unchain me and give me the trident.
如果你帮他解开 他就会跳下船 你永远也不要想见到他
If you unchain him, he'll jump off this boat, you'll never see him again.
赫淮斯托斯能帮你救出你的父亲
Hephaestus can help you save your father.
别让我们的家人失望
Don't let our family dawn.
从没有怀疑过你 阿格诺尔
Never doubted you for a second, Agenor.
伟大的库洛纳斯
Great Kronos.
父亲
Father.
我们把您的儿子 宙斯带来了
We have delivered Zeus, your sun...
按照您的指令
...as you ordered.
宙斯
Zeus.
凯尔岛
Island of Kail.
我不会再碰那个了
I'm not touching that again.
那是什么？
What is it?
我不知道 不管是谁这么做的 都不想让我们在这里
I dun'! know. But whoever did this doesn't want us here.
我们没有退路
We have no choice.
堕落之神不得不住的尽可能靠近天堂
Fallen god has to live as close to the heavens as possible.
有河流流过
Streams run through.
高地在那边
Higher ground's that way.
- 怎么了？ - 快看
What...?! Lack!
别动
Don't move!
我什么都看不到了
I can't see nothing.
我们应该向战神祈祷 战士们
We should pray to the god of war. - Warriors!
我知道这是你们的习惯 但是不管我们要面对的是什么
I know it is your custom, but no matter what we're about to face...
你不要向阿瑞斯祈祷
you do not pray to Ares.
如果你们这么做了 他会找到我们 把我们杀光
If you do, he will find us and kill us all.
靠近
Close in.
保持警惕
Stay alert.
绊网
Trip wire.
- 阿格诺尔! - 是的 是的 看到了
- Agenor! - Yeah, yeah. Saw it.
最重要的事就是什么都不要做
The most important thing is to do nothing.
没什么 我能做好
Nothing, I can do well.
啊为了宙斯之爱
Aah! For the lave of Zeus!
我告诉你什么都不要做
I told you to do nothing!
我什么也没做啊
I didn't do anything!
不 不 不
Na, nu, nu!
把负重砍掉
Cut the counterweights.
别砍掉负重
Don't cut the counterweight!
没错 他是对的 高空坠落会要了他的命
Yeah, he's right, the fall will kill him.
砍掉负重 砍掉负重
Cut the counterweight! Cut the counterweight!
阿格诺尔!
PERSEUS Agenor!
砍掉负重 砍掉负重
Cut the counterweight! Cut the counterweight!
阿格诺尔!
PERSEUS Agenor!
Agenor
哦 开什么玩笑
Oh, you gotta be kidding me.
趴下
Stay dawn!
啊
Ah!
那是什么？
What is it?
很大
Big.
安德洛墨达 把他打倒
Andromeda, slaw him dawn!
现在
NOW!
弓箭手
Archers!
加莱纳斯
Galenos...
- 去帮帮他 - 你 跟着我
- ... give him support. - You, fallow me.
不
Na!
我向您祈祷 伟大战神阿瑞斯 我向您祈祷
I pray to you, great god Ares. I pray to you-
嘘嘘
Shh.
它走了？
Is it gone?
嘿
Hey!
这不是个好主意
This is gonna be a bad idea.
我的兄弟在哪儿？
Where's my cousin?
很高兴你还活着吊在那儿
Glad you're hanging in there.
是啊 我以为我把他看了一个满眼
Yeah, I thought I'd give him an eyeful.
那边是在干什么？
What was that far?
海神波塞冬
Poseidon.
可怜的阿瑞斯 总是
Poor Ares, always...
遵循命令
following orders.
我自己说了算
I am my awn master.
是啊 当然你是
Yes, of course you are.
也许只是人类
Perhaps it's only humans...
才有自由意愿
...that have free will.
就是这个
There.
疼痛作为人类的教训
Pain! Your lesson in being human.
你为什么不哭？
Why don't you weep?
为什么你不像你宠爱的儿子珀尔修斯那样哭？
Why not weep like your favorite sun, Perseus?
如果我哭 那也是为了你 阿瑞斯
If I weep, it will be for you, Ares.
阿瑞斯
Ares.
住手
Enough.
为你的儿子哭泣吧
Weep for your son!
我说过
I said...
住手吧
enough!
这事你我都逃不了干系 哈迪斯
We are in this together, Hades.
不要现在就闹分歧
Dc not weaken now.
你的弱点就是你对你父亲和兄弟盲目的憎恨
Your weakness is your blind hatred for your father and your brother.
你不知道什么时候该停止战斗
You don't know when to stop fighting.
你已经赢了
You've already wan.
库洛纳斯在汲取宙斯的力量
Kronos is draining Zeus' power.
赫淮斯托斯
Hephaestus.
宙斯？
Zeus?
阿瑞斯
Ares!
哈迪斯
Hades!
终于我就知道你们会来
At last! I knew you'd came.
波塞冬 我能看到你的三叉戟在发光
Poseidon, I can see your trident glinting.
哈哈哈哈
Ha-ha-ha. Ah.
不是
It's not...
他们
...them.
我们在找赫淮斯托斯 那个
We're lacking for Hephaestus, the maker...
- 这样强力武器的制造者 - 好吧 我们要让他们进来么？
...of such mighty weapons. Well, should I let them in'?
他说了不行!
He says nu!
但是他总是说不
But then he always says nu.
他总是说
He always says...
不
...no.
啊
Ahh.
没错
Yes.
你是珀尔修斯
You are Perseus...
宙斯的儿子
son of Zeus.
是我
I am.
“击败北海巨妖怪”的那位
"Release the Kraken," all of that.
- 是 - 你是谁？
Yeah. - Who are you?
我是阿格诺尔 波塞冬之子
I'm Agenor, son of Poseidon.
阿格诺尔
HEPHAESTUS Agenor.
你有没有听说过阿格诺尔？
Have you ever heard of Agenor'?
从没听说过你
Never heard of you.
好吧 你的朋友也许听说过我的名头
Well, your friend may also know me by the name...
那个领航员
...the Navigator.
领航员？
Navigator?
领航员
Navigator!
还是不知道
Still nu.
别担心 孩子 他说有很多没有用的半神
Don't worry, son, he says there are many useless demigods.
“没有用”？和你独眼朋友们一样无用
"Useless"? About as useless as your one-eyed friends.
那些独眼巨人们
Those Cyclopes...
帮我铸造了神的武器
...helped me forge the god-weapons.
尊重一下他们
Have respect.
“领航员”
"Navigator. "
嗯
Mm-hm.
等等 因为…
Hold an, because...
波塞冬死了 宙斯被抓 那些监护者
Poseidon dead, Zeus captured. The wards...
甚至都没坐在一起
don't even sit together.
我们需要你的帮助解救宙斯
We need your help to rescue Zeus...
这样他就可以阻止库洛纳斯
so he can stop Kronos.
- 那就是计划 是么？ - 是的
- That's the plan, is it? Yeah.
好吧 既然这样 我们最好做好准备
Right. Right. Well, in that case, we'd best prepare.
为了什么？ 世界的终结
For what? - The end of the bloody world.
库洛纳斯会毁灭世界
Kronos will dismantle the earth.
你们会变成宇宙中飞散漂浮的碎片
You'll be scattered across the universe.
太棒了
Fantastic.
你铸造了这些武器
You forged these weapons...
就在这儿 为了众神 你一定能帮助我们
...right here for the gods. You must be able to help us.
闭嘴我还怎么能帮你们
Shut it! How could I...
当我已经没有了神的力量？
...when I've no godly power anymore?
他在和谁说话？
Who's he talking to?
你们不要
Don't you...
离开我
...walk away from me.
他全能的父亲把神的力量从我这儿夺走
His all-powerful father tank it away from me...
就因为在一次小的家庭纠纷中 我站在了哈迪斯一边
...when I sided with Hades in their little family argument.
没错 我知道那是一个错误
Yes, I know new it was a mistake!
人们会忘记
People forget!
最开始 哈迪斯很聪明
In the beginning, Hades was wise...
公正 强壮
...and just and strung.
如果不是因为你的父亲沉迷于力量
It were your daddy became drunk an power.
我们甚至希望
We were even hoping...
当宙斯来的时候 他会认清他的错误并恢复我们的
when Zeus came he might see his mistake and restore our...
为什么不？他会的 他会来的
Why not? He might have, had he came.
对不起
I'm sorry...
你以为作为人类远远不够.但是我们人类
...that you think being human is not enough. But we humans...
总是在没有希望的时候心存希望
hope when there's no hope.
在不该相信的时候坚信不移
And we believe when to believe is idiotic.
但是有时 不管
But sometimes, in spite...
怎么样 我们会战胜一切
of everything, we prevail.
现在
Now...
你们两个中
...which of you two...
谁说了算？
...is in charge?
- 我 - 那么
- I am. - Then...
如果我们是神
...if we were gods...
你会怎样帮助我们解救宙斯？
...how would you help us free Zeus?
哦 亲爱的
Oh, my dear.
你让我想起了某个人
You remind me of someone.
爱神阿佛洛狄忒
Aphrodite.
她是我的妻子
She was my wife.
跟我来
Came with me.
如果宙斯被囚抓到冥界
If Zeus is captive in the underworld...
他很有可能被困在地狱深渊的最深处
...he's likely being held in the heart of Tartarus.
在他的生命被完全侵蚀掉以前
There can't be much time before his life farce...
没有多少时间了
...is completely sapped.
我们怎么找到他？
But how do we get to him?
我们做不到
We can't.
正常情况下 你是对的 年轻人
Normally you'd be right, young man.
但是当我设计这个奇迹时
But when I designed this marvel...
我留下了一个秘密通道 一个捷径
...I included a secret passage, a shortcut...
如果你愿意那么叫的话
...if you will.
你设计的地狱深渊 哦 是的
- You designed Tartarus? Oh, aye.
我还亲自建造它
And built it.
阿佛洛狄忒 我能
Aphrodite, I could...
不仅把你们带进去
not only get you inside...
我还能带你们在里面参观一番
...I could give you a guided tour.
为了让地狱深渊的监狱
In order for the prison of Tartarus...
坚不可摧
...to be completely impregnable...
我是从外面开始向内建造
...I built it from the outside in.
所以我要给自己留个能够当工程完工时
So I had to leave a passage for meself to get cut...
全身出来的通道 这个迷宫
...when the work was done. And this labyrinth...
是人类能够穿越冥界
...is the only way a human can travel through the underworld...
而且能够到达地狱深渊最深处的唯一方式
...and get to the heart of Tartarus.
我那个狂吼的混蛋儿子阿瑞斯在哪儿？
Where's my snarling bastard of a sun Ares?
库洛纳斯已经放弃他了？
Will Kronos really spare him'?
还有你？
And you?
这就没个完么？
Is there no end to this?
我很害怕 兄弟
I'm afraid, brother.
你就想让我说这个？ 我是个神 我很还害怕
Is that what you want me to say? I'm a god and I'm afraid.
好吧 你应该的
Well, you should be.
当你珍贵的人类死掉时  至少他们的灵魂会去别处
When your precious humans die, at least their souls go to another place.
当一个神死掉时 那不是死亡
When a god dies, it isn't death.
只是遁入虚无
It's just absence.
什么都没有了
It's nothing.
永久的虚无
It's oblivion.
珀尔修斯
Perseus.
父亲
Father.
我很接近了
I'm close.
继续和我联系
Stay with me.
你看 如果你能正确地沿边缘排成一行
You see, if you align the edges correctly...
它会给你展示内部移动变换的样子
...it gives you a shifting depiction of the interior.
我可以说 这简直就是杰作
Can I say, that is a masterpiece.
好吧 对于画来说很受用
Well, useful to a paint.
- 能让卑微的领航员拿一会儿么？ - 不能
- Would you let a lowly navigator hold it? - Na.
好吧 你是波塞冬之子
Well, you are the sun of Poseidon.
是他教给我怎样导航的 怎样勾引
He's the one who taught me to navigate. That, and haw to seduce a mermaid...
偶尔出现的美人鱼 但实际上她们出现的频率
...which seemed random, but came in handy more often...
比你想象的频繁.要做的是
...than you'd think. Thing to dais...
别和她们说话 和她们的朋友说话
don't talk to her, talk to her friend.
领航员 这里就是迷宫的入口
Navigator, this is the entrance to the labyrinth.
有上百的门 所有的门都会杀了你们
There are hundreds of doors, all of which would kill you...
只有一个安全的门 你看
...save one. You see...
我设计这个是为了
...I designed it to play...
愚弄你们的心智 毕竟
...tricks with the mind. After all, the mind...
心灵是所有一切的最大陷阱
...is the greatest trap of all.
所以你们要控制你们的恐惧
Sc you've got to central your fears...
这样你们就不会背叛自己或者对方
so you don't turn on yourself or each other...
如果你们想要到达地狱深渊的话
...if you wanna make it to Tartarus.
到了
There it is.
这儿就是我们的门
There's our dour.
大家后退
Everybody back!
哦
Oh.
你们中谁对他祈祷过？
Which one of you prayed to him?!
你背叛了我们的父亲
You betrayed our father.
他背叛了我
He betrayed me...
因为他选择了你
...by choosing you.
你个大美人
You beauty!
快来啊它不会打开
Came an! It won't stay open...
很长时间的
...far lung!
不 不是现在
Na, not now!
伟大的神阿瑞斯
Great god Ares...
请您仁慈些 是我向您祈祷. 有人告诉我
...be merciful. It was I who prayed to you. I was taught...
不要向敌人祈祷 我衷心祈祷 因为你会在心中
...to pray for my enemies. I prayed you would find peace...
找到平静 啊啊
...in your hear... Ah! Ah!
我们是兄弟
We are brothers...
但是却不平等
...but not equal.
我要给他们争取多一点时间
I have got to give them more time.
最后一件神圣的东西
One last godly thing.
来啊
Came an!
让我看看你…
Let's see what you blee...!
珀尔修斯
Perseus!
赫淮斯托斯
Hephaestus.
啊
Aah!
赫淮斯托斯
Perseus! The door's...
- 门要关上了 - 快
...closing! Come on!
阿瑞斯
HEPHAESTUS Ares!
你就这点能耐
Is that all you got...
你个哭泣的
...you sniveling..
窝囊废？
...dag?
快到门那儿去
Get to the dour!
- 快 - 快
Came an! Came an!
哦 卡丽娜
Oh, Korrina.
她就是个傻瓜居然向他祈祷
She was a foal to pray to him...
可是他杀了弱者 他就是个胆小鬼
...and he was a coward to kill the weak.
他在很多战争中战斗过
He has fought in many wars.
许多世纪以来他总是残杀无辜
He's slaughtered innocents for centuries.
那就是所有
It's all...
他知道的事
...he knows.
我不能打败他
I can't beat him.
木头脑袋
Mutton head.
两天前 我被困在一个地牢的监狱里 不得不承认
Two days ago I was trapped in a cell in a dungeon, admittedly...
我试过逃跑 我不配做波塞冬的儿子
...trying to escape, unbecoming of the sun of Poseidon.
但是今天 我来到了这里 我要试着拯救这个世界
But today I'm here, and I'm trying to save the universe.
参与进来吧
Jump in.
殿下
Your Majesty...
我觉得迷宫里有数以百万计的可能性
...I realize in a labyrinth with a million possibilities...
但这是你最不想听到的
...this is the last thing you want to hear...
但是请跟紧我
...but fallow me.
那边
That way.
或者这边
Or this way.
我不知道
I don't know...
没有赫淮斯托斯我们怎么通过这里？
...haw we'll get through this without Hephaestus.
珀尔修斯
Perseus.
你的儿子在哪儿？
Where is your son?
这边
This way.
那边
That way.
这边
This way!
安德洛墨达
Andromeda.
卡丽娜
Korrina.
你必须回来
You must turn back.
这里本应该是
This should be...
一条走廊.这张地图讲不通
...a corridor. This map makes no sense.
安德洛墨达
Andromeda.
我们周围有什么东西
There's something in here with us.
- 把地图给我 - 不
- Just give me the map. - Na.
- 伟大的北海巨妖杀手 - 你不是应该在别的什么地方
The mighty Kraken slayer. Shouldn't he be somewhere...
- 为雕像摆姿势么？ - 阿格诺尔
- ... posing for a statue? - Agenor...
- 把地图给我 - 这张地图没有用
- ... just give me the map! - The map is useless!
这边
This way!
阿格诺尔!
PERSEUS Agenor!
我知道我们要走哪儿
I know where we're going!
这边
This way!
回来
Get back!
Back!
起来
Get up!
安德洛墨达
Andromeda!
对了
Yes.
支撑住
Take the weight!
快啊 快啊 快啊!
Came an, came an, came an!
走 快走!
Go, go!
走啊!
Go!
这儿很冷 不是么？
It's cold in here, isn't it?
你不是真实的
You're not real.
赫利俄斯？
Helius?
你为什么要这么做？ 求你了 爸爸 别杀我
Why are you doing this? Please, Dad, don't kill me.
- 珀尔修斯 - 珀尔修斯
Perseus! Perseus.
发生了什么？
What happened?
地狱深渊
Tartarus.
快 我们走
Came on, let's go.
快点
Came an.
库洛纳斯现在有自己的力量了
Kronos has his power now.
哈迪斯
Hades.
我很抱歉
I am so sorry.
为了什么？
For what?
驱逐你
For having banished you.
你能原谅我么？
Can you forgive me for that?
为什么要这么问？
Why do you ask?
因为我会为了这个而原谅你
Because I forgive you for this.
放开我 哈迪斯
Release me, Hades.
我知道你内心还是善良的
I know there is still good in you.
你真没有自尊 哈迪斯
You have no pride, Hades.
不
Na.
我不会让你杀了他
I won't let you kill him.
兄弟
Brother.
你阻止不了的
You can't stop this.
阿瑞斯
Ares!
快点
Came an.
走快走
Go, go!
父亲 父亲
Father. Father!
父亲
Father!
睁开眼睛
OPEN your eyes!
珀尔修斯
Perseus.
珀尔修斯 我的孩子
Perseus, my sun.
用你身体里的力量
Use the power inside you.
珀尔修斯
Perseus...
赶快
...hurry!
- 阿瑞斯 - 安德洛墨达
Ares! - Andromeda!
哈迪斯
Hades...
和我们来吧
...came with us.
不
Na!
哈迪斯
Hades.
武器 把武器给我
Weapon. Give it to me.
抓住他们
Hold them.
马提亚斯,干得不错
Mantius, impressive.
你集合了一只不错的军队 我已经准备皇家帐篷
- You gathered a fine army. - I have prepared a royal tent.
神住合适么？
And is it fit for a god?
伟大的宙斯 伟大的宙斯
Great Zeus. - Great Zeus.
伟大的宙斯
Great Zeus.
库洛纳斯
Kronos...
会来找我的 珀尔修斯
...will came for me, Perseus.
我没有力量来阻止他了
I don't have the power left to stop him.
我想
I wanted...
留给你一个安全的世界 但是我失败了
...to leave the world safe for you. I failed.
我原本应该和你一起的
I should have came with you.
- 我只是 - 你帮我
- I was just- You pulled me...
逃出了地狱深渊
out of Tartarus.
是你救了我
You saved me.
你怎么知道你会那么做？
How do you suppose you did that?
我从来没停止想过和我的儿子一起回家
I never stopped thinking about getting home to my sun.
那么使用它吧 为了你的儿子
Then you use that. Fight for your sun.
记住
Remember:
只有胜利之矛才可以击败库洛纳斯
Only the Spear of Trium can defeat Kronos.
而那双握着长矛的手
And the hand that holds that spear will have to be...
一定是你的
yours.
我们已经有了胜利之矛的两个部分
We have two pieces of the Spear of Trium.
波塞冬的三叉戟
Poseidon's trident...
哈迪斯的草叉
and Hades' pitchfork.
那么 我们还需要宙斯的闪电剑
Son, what we need is Zeus' thunderbolt.
就在阿瑞斯的背上背着
Which is an Ares' back.
没错
Yep.
阿瑞斯
Ares.
兄弟
Brother.
我向您祈祷
I pray to you.
在万神殿和我见一面
Meet me at the temple of the gods.
你说我们不平等
You say we're not equal.
那么来证明给我看
So come prove to me...
你是对的
...you're right.
证明给我们的父亲看 你是对的
Prove to our father that you're right.
兄弟 我听见你的话了
I hear you, brother.
我会拿到长矛 你要拖住他
I'll get the spear. You hold him off.
别给我讲长篇大论
Don't give me the big speech.
没错 我没有打算那么做
Yeah, I wasn't planning to.
我们的战斗计划
Our battle plan...
必须要简单
...must be simple.
防守的三条线：
Three lines of defense:
阿格诺尔的人守住前线
Agenor's men will hold the front line...
到战壕的区域
...from the trenches.
保护好身体的
Cover every part...
每个部分 不然你就会
of yourself, or you'll be burned...
引火焚身
...by the fire.
衣服的每一片布
Every piece of cloth...
每一片皮肤 互相帮助一下
...every piece of skin. Help each other.
后面的方阵
Phalanxes behind that...
和步兵队伍作为最后的防线
...and infantry as the last defense.
我会亲自率领步兵队
I will lead the infantry myself.
我们的职责
And our job...
是尽可能长的拖延库洛纳斯的时间
...is to hold Kronos back for as long as possible...
如果我们还要争取胜利的话
...if we're to stand a chance.
- 进战壕 - 全体就位
- Dig in! Position!
就位
Secure positions!
库洛纳斯在靠近
Kronos is near.
地狱兽
Makhai!
点火
Light the fires!
- 点火 - 点火
Light the fires! Light the fires!
稳住
Hold!
开火
Fire the artillery!
发射
Lease!
开火
Fire!
Brother. 兄弟
Brother.
兄弟
- 请别伤害他 - 我没打算伤害他
- Please don't hurt him. - I'm not going to hurt him.
我打算伤害你
I'm going to hurt you.
而且我想让他亲眼看着
And I want him to watch.
我想让你知道
I want you to know...
那种感觉
...what it feels like...
当有人把你的父亲从你身边夺走
...when someone takes your father away from you.
前线 进攻
Front line, attack!
跟住我
Stay with me!
稳住阵脚
Stand firm!
那么这就是父亲
Sc this is what a father...
和儿子要共同经历的么？
would go through for his son?
兄弟
Brother.
我
I do
原谅你了
forgive you.
你看起来好像
You lack...
年轻了一万岁
...10,000 years younger.
我感觉到了
And feel it.
死亡正在你身边萦绕
Death was circling you.
这是我最后一次我有力量将他驱逐了
That was the last time I'll have the strength to chase it away.
我们之间仍有力量
We have the power...
可以给大家展示一下
...between us to put an a little display.
就像很久以前一样
Like in the old days.
那么我们来一起结束一切？
Sc shall we finish this?
我们没有武器
We have no weapons.
我们有武器之前都有力量
We had power before we had weapons.
- 当我们还是年轻的神 - 没错
- When we were young gods. - Yes.
我们去开心一下吧
Let's have some fun!
赫利俄斯 武器
Helius. Weapons!
稳住阵线稳住阵线
Hold the line! Hold the line!
保持阵型
Stand firm!
胜利之矛
The Spear of Trium.
哈迪斯
Hades.
宙斯
Zeus.
第一击是为了我自己 兄弟
The first strike's mine, brother.
珀尔修斯
Perseus!
现在一起吧 兄弟
Together now, brother!
这就是了 伙计 他们给我们争取了一个机会
This is it, bay. They've given us a chance.
兄弟
Brother!
快 站起来
Came an, stand up!
珀尔修斯珀尔修斯珀尔修斯
Perseus! Perseus! Perseus!
他在等着你
He's waiting for you...
在他走之前
before he goes.
你的孩子给了你力量
Your bay gave you strength.
是的
Yes.
我的也是
As did mine.
或许哈迪斯能治好你
Perhaps Hades can heal you.
他已经给了我最后一次机会
He already gave me my last chance.
你为了他牺牲了一切
And you sacrificed it for him.
不会再有更多的牺牲
There will be no more sacrifices.
不再有神
Na more gods.
正确使用你的力量 珀尔修斯
Use your power wisely, Perseus.
谢谢你 我的孩子
Thank you, my sun.
我所有的力量都已用光
All my power is spent.
谁知道？
Who knows?
没有力量 我可能只是个路人
I might be stranger without it.
我知道这是刹车 没有必要告诉我
I know it's brake. Na need to tell me.
我要靠他生存 但是我妈妈说
I could walk an it, but... My mum always said...
你要让每个人都有他发光的时刻 你知道么？
...you should let everyone have their moment to shine. You know?
那么 你知道 我已经功成名就 我已经有了名头
So, you know, I'm established. I've already got a name.
你知道？航海家
You know? The Navigator.
如果我没记错
If I'm not mistaken...
你是珀尔修斯的儿子 我是赫利俄斯
- ... you're the son of Perseus - I am Helius.
那就是你的孩子么 赫利俄斯？
Is that your bay, Helius?
过去那边
Go over there!
赫利俄斯
Helius!
过来
Came here.
我要给你讲个故事 过来见见
I've got a story to tell. Came and meet...
你们的叔叔航海家
your Uncle Navigator.
我是阿格诺尔
I'm Agenor.
赫利俄斯
Helius.
我听说你是个很大的败笔
I've read that you are a great disappointment.
没错 我很伟大
That's right, I am great.
这是我的护士 泰戈尔
This is my nurse, Tiger.
如果还有另外一次袭击的话 我们要做好准备
We have to be prepared if there's another attack.
我们用第三军团加强了阿尔戈斯城
We're fortifying Argos with the third regiment.
我们的敌人会在两天内做好准备 所以在西方 我们可以…
Our engines will be ready in two days, so in the west we can...
父亲
Dad...
实际上我正要回家
...I'm actually lacking forward to going home.
我决定作为一名赤脚渔夫也不是个坏事
I've decided being a baring fisherman isn't that bad.
你知道我们不能回家
You know we can't go back home.
拿着它
Take it.
你是赫利俄斯
You're Helius.
你是珀尔修斯的儿子
You're sun of Perseus...
宙斯的孙子
...the grandson of Zeus.
拿着它
Take it.
很重
It's heavy.
是的 没错
Yeah, it is.
是不是太重了？
Is it too much?
也不是
Na.